# -curriculum vitae

# Mahmoud Mohamed Zakria

# Front-end developer

My personal website http://zakcoding.com

Address: 26 Qenawi's Corner, El-Sheikh Rehan street

Abdeen, Cairo, Egypt

Date of birth: 11/06/1990

me@zakcoding.com Mobile: 01007558829 Marital Status: Single Military Status: Exempted

"I've been coding and building websites/apps for more than 4 years and I'm passionate about anything related to the web industry. I'm a team player, self-motivated, never stop learning and adore new challenges."

## Education

## Thebes Academy-Higher Institute of Computer Science and Management

- Bachelor's degree Of Management Information Systems "Aug 2011"
- Grade: Very Good GPA: 3.36

#### Skills

- HTML5, CSS/CSS3 and JavaScript "ES6 new features" are my main profession.
- UI/UX principles and trends like "Flat design & Material Design", Responsive web design and some of SEO.
- CSS preprocessors: **SASS**, **Stylus**.
- For JavaScript frameworks: **Angular**, **Vue.js**.
- For build system and task runner: **Gulp**, **Grunt** sometimes I use **npm** scripts.
- For modules bundler: Browserify, Rollup, webpack.
- For template engines: good knowledge in **Mustache/Handlebars** and **Jade/pug**.
- For static pages generator: **Jekyll**.
- Good knowledge in SVG and SMIL the animation for SVG.

## Work experiences

- Worked at cybercafé as a cashier and technical 9/2010 Till 11/2011.
- Worked at **Mobinil/Orange** as a call center representative, point of sales help line **16/5/2012 Till 29/8/2013** .
- Worked as graphic designer at Mohazzabon organization 1/6/2014 Till 1/7/2016.
- Worked as junior front-end web developer at Diva-lab 23/6/2014 Till 31/1/2016.
- Worked as senior front-end web developer at Diva-lab 31/1/2016 Till 1/8/2016.
- Worked as front-end web developer at Kite agency 25/9/2016 Till 11/10/2016.

- Worked as a front-end web developer at Betahubs 7/12/2016 Till 5/1/2016.
- Working as front-end developer at Mondia-Media 10/1/2017 Till now.

## Achievements

My Stuff

## css library (give.css)

https://github.com/mahmoudZakaria90/give

#### **ShortSnippets.css**

https://mahmoudzakaria90.github.io/shortSnippets/public/

#### **U-build.js**

https://mahmoudzakaria90.github.io/u-build/public/

#### My codePen samples

http://codepen.io/Mahmoud-Zakaria/

#### Assassin's code collection

https://mahmoudzakaria90.github.io/assassinCode/public/

## Javascript API for UI developing

http://codepen.io/Mahmoud-Zakaria/post/assassin-s-code-js-full-intro

#### **Mv Github**

https://github.com/mahmoudZakaria90

#### Bestyflow 1&2(My workit)

https://github.com/mahmoudZakaria90/besty-flow https://github.com/mahmoudZakaria90/besty-flow2

## • **Projects I** contributed in

Diva-lab: my company website

https://www.diva-lab.com

**Zewail City: my first step website** 

https://www.zewailcity.edu.eg

## Nutrition planet Dr.sherifa abo-elfoutoh

http://nutritionplanet.info

## Art of form

http://art-of-form.com

#### **3atayer**

https://3atayer.com

#### CIAAS

http://ciaas.ca/

## **PPLMX**

http://pplmx.com : splash page

http://pplmx.com/eprogram/ : pplmx home page

# Master master-piece (first web animation based)

http://masterpiece-eg.com/main/index.php

#### Medicare

http://www.medicareegypt.com/

## **Road9online**

http://road9online.com/

## MLS: Misr language school

http://mls-egypt.org

## **Arab Organization for constitution**

http://dustour.org

## **Arab Federation For Libraries and Information**

http://www.arab-afli.org

## Wajbety: online food order system based

http://Wajbety.com

## **Portal library**

http://diva-lab.com/projects/library/index.html

#### **New Motors**

http://diva-lab.com/projects/newmotores/index.php

#### Hilton

http://www.diva-lab.com/projects/hilton/index.php?lang=en

#### **Verona**

http://diva-lab.com/projects/verona/index.html

## Rodymar

http://www.rodymar.com/

#### **Cairo beats**

http://cairobeatsfm.com/

# Language

Arabic : Mother Tongue English : Very Good